FATIMA MODUPE BELLO

Frontend Developer(ReactJs)

https://www.linkedin.com/in/techietee https://github.com/techietee https://www.techietee.dev Lagos, Nigeria mailtomodupe@gmail.com +2349031703106

Professional Summary

In my Professional years of Experience as a Frontend Engineer, I have worked on Software Products, getting involved from the design phase to the deployment phase in agile cross-functional teams. My long-term goal is to build, maintain and understand market needs for software products that would transform businesses.

Technical Skills

Programming languages/Frameworks/Technologies: JavaScript ES6, HTML, CSS, React js, Vue js, Styled Component, CSS libraries, Storybook for documentation, React test tools, Responsive Web applications, Data Structures, Algorithms, Object-Oriented Programming.

Tools: Git, Bitbucket, JIRA & Confluence, Trello, Open Project, VS Code, Figma, Webpack, Babel, Git Actions, Docker, Postman, Swagger docs, Chrome Dev Tools.

Work Experience

Frontend Engineer, Enyata, Lagos, NG (March 2022 – Present)

Enyata provides software products as a service, and provides mentorship, in the Enyata Software Academy.

- AQ application is an Identity Verification Platform that ensures the legitimacy of customer accounts.
- Technologies: SCSS, JavaScript, Postman, Trello, React, Typescript, Nextis
- Deploying front-end applications to production, displaying and manipulating data from APIs on the client-side, end-to-end testing, building UI functional components, and handling code reviews.

Frontend Engineer, Hardcore Biometric Systems, Abuja, NG (September 2020 – March 2022)

Hardcore Biometric Systems is a software development company that builds and maintains software products.

- The 7 microservice applications aid the Nigerian Police Force to carry out criminal investigation and execution processes seamlessly, beginning from incident reports, to enrollment and other applications for the same purpose.
- Technologies: JavaScript, Reactjs, React Query, Redux, Context, Storybook, Maven, Jenkins CI, Git, Jira
- Introduced and implemented a design system with React Storybook that improved consistency in development and aided new developers onboarding by a larger percentage across various teams.
- Built and deployed micro-frontend web application using microservices, Handled state management and UI logic using React hooks, and documented components as a style guide using React Storybook.

- Translate designs and wireframes into high-quality code, built functional reusable components using React js and styled component, and worked with REST APIs from Swagger docs to integrate with the frontend.
- Documented task flow and process improvements in Confluence, and updated task progress on Jira.
- Designed and developed the company's website, creating a user-friendly interface that is fully responsive and optimized for search engine indexing and useability.
- Learned the agile workflow from design to deployment as well as presenting features at demo sessions.

Junior Software Developer, Centrifuge Group, Abuja, NG (March 2020 – September 2020)

With vast experience and an excellent track record, Centrifuge group has positioned itself as an ideal solution for all software development projects.

- Technologies: JavaScript, PHP, MySQL, Linux, Ubuntu
- Identified UI problems, and fixed bugs on the existing codebase on Bchip and Dhis2 from the client's feedback.
- Upgraded, deployed, and troubleshoot Bchip application giving room for continuous improvement.
- Learned to use the terminal and Linux OS.

Frontend Developer Intern, Ihifix Technologies, Kaduna, NG (March 2019 – March 2020)

Ihifix Technologies builds software products for users and businesses

- Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Figma, WordPress
- Built and maintained business websites for clients with WordPress.
- Implemented UI prototypes/designs for multiple in-office web-based applications using Figma.

Software Developer Intern, Nigeria Communication Satellite, Abuja, NG (**June 2017 – December 2017**)

NIGCOMSAT manages and operates the first quad-band communications satellite in sub-Saharan Africa.

- Developed a working knowledge of front and back-end technologies through self-guided tutorials, with an emphasis on object-oriented programming and databases.
- Designed and developed a Visitor's Login System, this system solved the problem of unscheduled guests coming into the organization's premises.
- Learned DOTNET, MySQL, JavaScript, asynchronous programming, and the concept of web technology

Education

B.Tech(2018) in Information Technology - Federal University of Technology, Minna.

Languages

English - Native Language

Volunteer Experience

Mentor on the International Online Frontend Foxes Bootcamp cohort 3 - August 2022